<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Erek Cyr</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-29">September 29,2016</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-08-31">August 31, 1905</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, AUGUST 31, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T.
                    1.
                </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement">
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">


      THE EGYPTIAN GAZirPTB, THURSDAY, AUQ1TST 31, 1905.
      .YESTERDAY’S TOTAL SOLAR ECLIPSE.
      • . *
      DE3TAILED REPORTS IF1 IR, O IM ASSOUAN,
      ALEXANDRIA, CAIRO, PORT SAID, SUEZ, AND EDFOU.
      SiieeeHsFiil OI:>ser>vrGttioi?s Fnoro Zorns of WobGilit^.
      PROMINENCES AND STREAMERS CLEARLY SEEN.
      AT ASSOUAN.
      (From odr Special Correspondent).
      (By Telegraph)
      Assonan, Wednesday.
      This afternoon’s • eolipse was a thorongh
      success, if I may be allowed to nse the ex-
      pression, and whatever the scientific results
      obtain ed, there can be no doubt that the con-
      ditions were as favorable to observation as
      they well could be. The wind was very light,
      and not a single cloud was visible during the
      whole afternoon, though there a certain hazi-
      ness about. Haze was of course almost inev-
      itable at this season of the rising Nile flood,
      but I have not been informed that it apprecia-
      bly interfered with observations^ Numerous
      observers were in the field. Besides the scien-
      tific parties and commissions, not a - few
      energetic amateurs had braved the heat and
      discomfort of a long railway journey to go
      south to Assouan. Mr. Smyrnoff, the Russian
      Diplomatic Agent in Egypt, Count Arrivabene
      Gonzaga, the Acting Diplomatic Agent for
      Italy, Graft Antonio von Stadnioki, Secretary
      of Legation to the Austro-Hungarian Diplo-
      matic Agenoy, and M. Roman Ertbuer, secre-
      tary to the Belgian Consulate General, left
      Cairo on Monday evening and arrived at the
      Savoy Hotel last night, while Mr. Mitohell
      Innes, who gives a dinner to all the astrono-.
      mical missions to-night, Mr. A. L. Webb,
      C.M.G., and Mr. Courtenay Clifton were also
      among the spectators. The Egyptian Go-
      vernment mission was divided. Mr. Wade
      watched the eolipse from a height west of
      Assouan, while Mr. Freeman’s station was
      near Edfou, and Mr. Macpherson and Yonssef
      Etfendi Fordi were at Dauhid south of the
      first cataract.
      The members of the various scientific mis-
      sions were early on the ground. Special police-
      men and barriers of rope kept the meet carious
      at a distance from the astronomers and their
      instruments, and long before the eolipse began
      all was in the most perfeot readiness for the
      great event.
      At 3.26 p.m. came the moment of first con-
      o tract and thereafter the blact line of the
      moon’s shadow gradually gained on the glowing
      brightness of the sun. The progress of the
      eclipse was followed with intense interest and
      it must have seamed years to the more impa
      tient observers before the phase of totality was
      reached at 4.36 p.m. Ror two minutes and
      twenty four seconds the sun was completely
      hidden. Several stars were plainly visible and
      the planet Mars was remarkably conspicuous.
      Animal life was absolutely still in the gloom,
      but for one flock of birds that passed overhead.
      The corona afforded a most interesting
      v - stndy. The streamers were most prominent in
      the sun spot zones, the western streamers being
      shorter and more divergent, the longest, being
      quite two diameters of the sun in length. Short
      streamers of light were also visible proceeding
      from the north and south polar extremities
      of the sun. The prominences notioed were
      particularly large, especially those which
      issued from the weetem side of the obscured
      sun.
      Then the bright edge of the sun began to
      emerge and the important part of the eclipse
      was over. Nothing is known as yet of the
      results obtained by the scientists who were at
      work in recording magnetic observation,and as
      the photographic results await development it
      is impossible to give anything like a complete
      description of what has actually been recorded
      by the instruments. Further details will follow;
      iu the meantime the eolipse may be pronounced
      a sucre-» from every point of view.
      . i	'	ii';'
      NOTICE.
      The latest telegrams, with
      to-day’s local and general, and
      financial news, will be found
      on page 5,
      AT ALEXANDRIA.
      In Alexandria, as in every other town and
      village of Egypt, a keen interest was taken in
      the eclipse, which was the topic of the day in
      some circles, and in others was a close second
      either to the Peace or the effects of M.
      Cronier’s suicide. Interest, indeed, is hardly
      a strong enough term for the emotions that was
      stirred in the breasts of many Alexandrians by
      the realisation of the fact that at one minute
      to threa in the afternoon a partial eclipso of
      the snn would commence, without fail, — for
      such events are never postponed—and that led
      even bootblacks and marartons to arm them-
      selves with pieces of smoked glass. As the
      time of the commencement of the eclipse drew
      near, the streets, in some of the quarters, were
      fall of individuals braving a snnstroke or the
      wheels of the passing arabeahs in wild anxiety
      lest the moment of oontact should pass un-
      observed. Many photographic records were
      taken, and the majority of those which we
      have seen have been highly successful, port-
      raying the crescent-like appearance of the
      eclipsed sun with great accuracy.
      Those who knew. nothing of science, and
      merely regarded the sun as a provider of light
      and heat, and to whom the statement that the
      earth moves round the bod is as improbable
      as its oontrary is unimportant, anticipated the
      event with a certain uneasiness. They had
      an idea that something was going to happen
      to “Eshshems,” they had been told that its
      diso would be almost entirely hidden from
      their view, and that day would become night,
      and behoving all, .they brooded nneasily over
      what would happen, and wondered what it
      would all look like.
      How disappointed they must have been !
      Unable to appreciate that the sun, while com-
      pletely hidden at Assouan, would be only
      partially obsonred at Alexandria and other
      stations even closer to the zone of totality,"
      they bad hoped or feared that a great and
      solemn darkness would pass over the earth,
      attended by rare and ourions portents.
      Bnt all they saw was a black something
      that came into contact with the rim of the
      son’s disc and ate ita way into the fiery circle,
      disposing like a glutton of more and more till,
      in the words of a spectator, “the sun looked
      like a huge cheese from which a great piece had
      been bitten.” Snch was the eclipse to many
      of the smoked-glass enthusiasts.
      The morning opened hazily enough, but the
      sky cleared as the day grow older, and the
      conditions at the aotnal moment of the eolipse
      were as favorable as any observer could desire.
      We chose the Ras el Tin lighthouse as oar
      point of observation, obtained admittance,
      thanks to the kind offices of Admiral Sir R.M.
      Blomfield, and began oar olimb. The extreme
      effort of olimbing 261 steps to the summit,
      was right well repaid, and bad there-been no
      eolipse we should never have regretted it,
      for the view from the platform just below
      the light is the best in Alexandria. The
      ooast from San Stef&no to Fort Agami the
      grey town, the’harbour with its shipping and
      quays and the Mariont Lake, white with salt
      incrustations west of the canseway, a dull
      greenish grey to tbe' east, were all stretched
      below ns, wonderfully clear and distinct despite
      the haze that drew in from seaward, and in
      the harbour below the white sails of the raoing
      boats passed like swans.
      At the first moment of contact nothing—hat
      a violent and painful glare—was visible to
      the naked eye, nor oould the smoked glass
      show ns anything, but being provided with a
      fairly strong telescope with smoked lenses, we
      were able to follow the progress of the moon’s
      shadow from start to finish. The first sign of
      tbe eolipse that we oonld discern was a
      peculiar jaggeduess in the Ban's oiroumferenoe.
      This was notioeable shortly after 3 p.m.—
      the first oontact taking place at 2 h. 59 min.
      41 seo. The shadow moved forward very
      slowly bnt by 3.80 p.m. a certain diminution
      in tbe sun’s light and heat was apparent, and
      the glasses showed that the oironlar edge of
      the moon had made considerable progress.
      The effeot of the diminution of the sun’s
      light was first obvious shortly after 8.80 p.m,
      when the oolonrs of the sea and shore, wbiob
      had previously been warm and glowing, began
      to wane and, if the expression may be need,
      to fade. It was not thatr the aotnal colour of
      oVjeots really ohanged, but that its intensity
      diminished.
      This feature increased with the progress of
      tbe eclipse, bnt it was not possible to dis-
      tinguish any ohaogt of odour till ihortly
      before 4 p.m., when the obscuration was near-
      ing its maximum. The sea was then a dead
      slaty green iu the harbonr, a remarkably
      beautiful violet near the horizon, a dark
      blue green in the middle distanoe.The Mariont
      Lake had completely lost its oolour, and
      objects on the shore seemed to be suffused
      with a slight shade of yellow. At the time
      of maximum obscuration, the sun had shrunk
      to a crescent which appeared to be a little
      larger than the new moon. No stars were
      visible, at least from oar vantage point. The
      day was now decidedly dull, bat not in the
      least dark; distant objeots, though their colour
      had in some degree faded or altered, being
      just as distinguishable as at midday. In the
      towu, owing to the abundance of shade from
      houses and the narrowness of many of the
      streets the effect was oertainly more marked,
      but we imagine that many of the observers
      must have felt a certain disappointment at
      being able to dispense with artioial light;
      indeed the strongest impression left on ns
      was that of the immense power of the solar
      light evon when reduced to 12% of ita original
      volume.	• , ■
      The recovery from the obaouration does not
      meric special description. The light returned
      very rapidly, and within half an hoar from the
      moment of maximum obscuration everything
      had regained its normal appearance. One
      result of the eolipse whioh we notioed, was
      more durable, the later afternoon though as
      damp as it always is in the autumn months,
      being muoh cooler than usual.
      AT CAIRO. »
      (From our own Correspondent.)
      Cairo, Wednesday.
      The early morning yesterday was as dull
      and cloudy in Cairo as it usually is at this
      period, bnt at about eight o’clock the at-
      mosphere become quite clear and oontinned
      so for the rest of the day, which was for-
      tunate for those anxious to have a good
      view of the phenomenon which, with one or
      two others subjects, has been the ohief
      topio of conversation for the past week or
      two, not only amongst Europeans bnt also
      the educated portion of the native popula-
      tion.
      • *
      Among the lowest classes of the latter the
      most extraordinary notions seemed to prevail
      as to the cause of the wonder that was abont
      to happen and its conseqnenoes. Some of the
      more vigorous observers of religion uttered
      prayers all the while. In the purely native
      quarters, troops of children with a few adnlts
      as well perambulated the streets, beating tom-
      toms and invoking divine protection.
      In Cairo the eolipse was only partial bat
      about nine-tenths of the snn’s diso was covered
      and this took place at thirteen minutes past
      four when the light became much dimmer,
      somewhat resembling a very bright moon-
      light evening or the shortened twilight of this
      t'me of the year. It oommenoed at four
      minutes past three and the eolipse ended at
      a quarter past five o’olook. These were the
      times famished by the Survey Department
      which, however, differed slightly from those
      given by the eminent astronomer, M. Busoa-
      loni, and published by us last Friday. Most of
      the Europeans witnessed the phenomena from
      thp house tops with smoked glasses, without
      whioh it was not possible, even when the
      eolipse was at its fullest to look at the sun
      with the naked eye with any comfort.
      A Mahomedan writer of abont a century
      back recounts that a total eolipse of the sun in
      his time exoited veritable terror amongst (h*
      population of Cairo, many people being so.
      alarmed as to hide themselves in barricaded
      rooms. He likewise relates that animals and
      birds seemed as snsoeptible os human beings,
      and doubtless had fear at the disappearance of
      the sun.	.
      If this year’s bad been also a total eolipse
      many strange sights would have been witnessed
      in the metropolis amongst the illiterate native
      population. Aooording to another writer plant*
      and flowers were influenced by the phenomen a
      and the leaves of those plants that olose a
      night did the aas daring an eolipse that oo»
      ourred in his day. Whether suoh be .a fact or
      not it is for the astronomers of to-day to
      galighten us.
      ‘ V"	‘ • •
      . .* . .
      AT PORT SAID.
      (From odr own Correspondent).
      Port Said, Wednesday.
      Very considerable interest has been taken
      in Port Said in the great event of to-day, and
      the question of the eolipse has been the chief
      topio of conversation with almost everyone.
      Telescopes of all sorts and sizes were hastily
      prepared with little pieces of smoked orcolonred
      glass, and on all hands, almost since the day
      broke, one could observe people gazing at the
      snn, as though they could not depend upon
      scientists to have fixed the time accurately.
      Even the Arab bootblack seems to have heard
      that somethiog.out of the common was abont
      to happen, and with a certain amount of
      doubt and apprehension looked upwards
      wondering, and expecting he knew not what.
      The day broke in anything bnt a reassnring
      manner. Banks of cloud and mist had gathered
      over the Bky, making the morning like an
      October one in England. This mist and damp
      in the air is hot surprising in a way and indi-
      rectly is nndontedly caused by the eolips e itself.
      The cause of tides, as is well known, is due to
      the joint attraction of the sun and moon, and
      when the two bodies aot in oonjunotion, as they
      do in a direct line daring an eclipse, the effeot
      is a much higher tide than nsnal. Anyone
      here, who has watohed the un behaviour
      lately, will have notioed how much higher the
      water has stood in the early evening, and this
      has caused a quite unwonted humidity and
      resultant mist for the last two mornings.
      I explain this point as I have heard several
      people daring the last few days, propound deep
      theories on the weather changes whioh aocom-
      pany eclipses. It was not the direct influence of
      the eolipse on the weather whioh caused the
      misty day, bnt the peonliar situation of loner
      Egypt, having so mnch semi marshy land which
      covers and unoovers with the slightest tidal
      variation.
      Long before the critical hour of first oontact
      approached (the time at which the moon’s diso
      tonohed the extreme edge of that of the sun )
      numbers of people oould ha seen wash-
      ing for the snn’s appearanoe through then
      specially prepared shades and glasses. The
      hour, as published iu the “Gazette," of 3.13
      p.m. passed and few were aware of it,
      for without a good teleioope fitted with
      suitable shades, and without the observer
      knowing exactly where to look, it is more
      than likely he would have seen nothing
      of the herald of this wonderful phenomena. I
      was perhaps a little more fortunate than many,
      having at my disposal a very good “Ross
      panoratio” glass properly fitted up, aided by
      whioh I easily saw and noted the first oontaot,
      whioh ocourred at 8h. 12m. 40skc. p.m.
      Nothing particular was to be noted during
      the first few minutes, exoept the gradual
      enoroaohment of the dark serrated-edged mass
      of the moon on the bright solar diso, bnt
      towards fonr o’olook, daylight had very sensi-
      bly diminished and tone dial objeots had begun
      to take on themselves the weird, lurid, half
      eleotrio type of light whioh is sopeonliarly charac-
      teristic of these eolips cb. This strange oolour
      whioh everything rapidly took as time moved
      onwards appeared to resemble nothing so muoh
      as the hue whioh obj iota have during the
      lightning flashes of a heavy thunderstorm, the
      daylight becomiug less and less as moments
      sped on towards the hour of maximum eclipso.
      By 4.16 p.m.over 76 per oent.of the son’s light
      had been oat off.
      The oaloulated hoar for Port Said of 4.26
      p.m., at whioh the maximum eolipse was to
      take place, seemed to pass without any special
      . notice being taken of it by the layman, as, for
      some moments before, owing to the effects of
      irradiation, by virtue of whioh all bright
      objeots to the naked eye appear muoh larger
      than they really are, the blank diso of the
      moon Beemed to the nnaided eye to have
      almost oeased to move,
      The sup at 4.20 p.m, greatly resembled a
      very bright new moon, having in its arms an
      opaque' diso suoh as is frequently seen at tbe
      period of perigee, when, oembined with salt-
      ,able weather conditions, the new moon appeata
      to hold the old one in ita arms.
      In Port 8aid to-day there was no sign of the
      oorona whioh waa eagerly looked for by many,
      and maty people seemed disappointed that
      the day oontinned so light, bat it was hardly
      aarpriiiog, w&sn one oonaiders that only IT
      minutes of arc were out off. Near the south-
      western edge, however, a faint extended
      phosphorescence oonld be seen, as I have stat-
      ed. A planet for which I was on the look out,
      was to be seen to the south, and I fancied I
      oould piok up another, Venus, olose to the
      western horiton. bnt was not .sure.
      Regulus, a star of the firat magnitude, si tout-
      ed only a few degrees west of the two bodies,
      I oonld not piok up, nor did I see any of the
      nnmerons smaller ones whioh in totality
      should have been clearly visible,— and so passed
      the best of what we saw here of the eolipse.
      By 4.45 p.m. most people appearei to have
      got tired of watching, especially as every
      minute increased the size of the sun’s visib’e
      cresoent, and the consequent brightness of
      daylight, and all seemed to think that nothing
      more waa to be seen.
      The moment ot last oontact when the moon
      finally left the eastern edge of the son, occur-
      red at the predicted time, 5.22 p.m. Then
      oame the sunset, whioh, I have noticed, on the
      day of solar eo ipses generally has a beauty all
      its own. The damp air here is peculiarly suited
      for these beantifnl effeots and as the glowing
      orb sank in the west .into a somewhat hazy
      horizon, the sky took on the same gloomy
      refjta, yellows and dark bines extending to
      the eastern horizon.
      AT SUEZ.
      (From odr Correspondent.)
      . • <
      (By Telegraph).
      Suez, Wednesday.
      The conditions under whioh the eclipse of
      the snn was viewed from this station were
      exceedingly favorable. The sky was perfectly
      clear and not a cloud was to he seen, and
      though there was a slight haze it did not
      interfere in any way with the observatioi s
      taken here.
      It is safe to say that the eolipse was viewed
      by everybody in Suez, smoked glasses were
      everywhere in evidence, and an altogether
      remarkable interest was taken in the pheno-
      menon.
      The shadow of the moon was first observed
      in contact with the sun at eight minutes past
      three by Cairo time or eight minutes past one
      by Greenwioh time, and it disappeared at
      thirteen minutes past five by Cairo time. The
      direction waa S. S. E. 81° west.
      At no time did darkness reech any great
      degree, but as the sun became gradually more
      and more hidden the temperature grew appre-
      ciably cooler, and a ovrioua effeot, of whioh I
      have never seen the parallel, was observable.
      The light became muoh less intense and
      resembled neither night nor day, objeots
      assumed a peculiar ont line, and the oolonr, cr
      oolo rs, I should say, of the sea were indescrib-
      able.	; t
      The horizon was particularly notioeable. As
      the solar diso gradually disappeared from view,
      a haziness appeared, and the oatline, whioh
      daring most of the day had been well-defined,
      was first of all blurred, and it then became
      difficult to distinguish, and at the same time
      assumed a greyish-blue tint.
      There was, however, at the plaoe where the
      rays from the nnobscured portion of the sun
      lit upon the sea, a bright light, in strange
      contrast to its surroundings, and of an almost
      silver hne, whioh gave an excellent effeot.
      In the town itself, I am told, an almost better
      effeot was obtained than iu the open space
      from whioh I observed the eolipse,for here there
      was a greater degree of darkness, whioh from
      a popular point of view, is the greatest feature,
      of suoh a phenomenon, be it total, or bo it
      partial, andno little oonsternatiottWas apparent
      amongst some of the more yonthfal observers,
      who were nnable to understand suoh a strange
      ooonrrenoj in broad daylight.
      The astronomists who witnessed the eolipse
      from here were all amateurs, so that one cannot
      hope for an authentio aooount of the phenomena
      presented, bnt tbe eolipse did not reach a
      sufficient degree of totality to render them
      worthy of a speoial reoord. It has, however,
      bean an event of great interest to amateur
      astronomers and physioiats, and many of
      these, who were unable to go to that zone
      where their enthusiasm would have met with
      more valuable results, will have interesting
      reoorda ot the great event of 1905 as seen at
      Sen,	1
      AT EDPOU.
      (From odr Correspondent).
      (By Telegraph).
      ' Edfou, Thursday.
      The total solar eclipse began here yesterday
      afternoon at forty minutes past three.Totality,
      whioh was reaohed at twenty-two minutes past
      fonr, lasted for the spaoe of sixty-eight seoonds.
      The eolipse ended at forty five minutes past
      five. Numerous observers watohed the pheno-
      menon from here and speoial magnetic obser-
      vations were taken from the roof of the great
      temple here. The results showed that no **
      speoial magnetic disturbances took plaoe daring
      the eclipse.
      THE TRACK OF THE SHADOW.
      The shadow of the moo 3, a vast oironlar
      patch, covering an area of somo 1,700 sqnare
      miles (a little larger than Switzerland), that is
      to say abont 130 miles in diamster, first struck
      the earth at sui.rue somewhere near Winni-
      peg, in Canada, and just skirting tho southern
      shores of Hadron Bay its centre reaohed the
      Atlantio on the coast of Labrador, near Domi-
      no Harbour. Traversing the ooean it first
      tonohed the European Continent on the north
      ooast of Spain near Luaroa, and passing in a
      south-easterly direction through Burgos and
      Ateca, reaohed the Mediterranean at Oro-
      pesa; end, involving the Baleario Islands
      in its gloom, it reaohed the Afrioan ooast
      near Philippeville in Algeria. Passing aoross
      the north-east oorner of Tunis it again
      crossed the sea at Sfax, and skirting the
      Afrioan coast between Tripoli and the Gulf of
      Sidra traversed a portion of the Libyan
      Desert, passing aoross Egypt, Assouan being
      naar the centre line; and orossing the Red
      Sea abont the middle of its length passed
      into Arabia, where it died away cetr the ooast
      of the Indian Ooean, where it set eolipsed.
      PROSPECTS OF VALUABLE RESULTS. /
      • ■.»
      It is five years and a quarter sinoe a total
      eolipse of the snn oonld be observed within snoh
      easyreaoh ofthe oapitalsof Europe and America,
      and in that interval the progress of physioal
      soienoe, as well as the perfection of instruments
      connected therewith, have made great strides,
      and, while thediseoveryof radium and the inves-
      tigations of its allied radic-aotive substances
      have opened up rv together new fields of re-
      search in phypierf cUmistry, the rapid advan-
      ces whioh h\ve been made during reoant years
      in the electrical theory of matter, together with
      the greatly extended application of the speo- 1
      troscope to solar and -stellar physics, all bid
      flair to cpnfor on this eolipse an unpreosdented
      value for its po isible results.
      SHADOW BANDS.
      There is an interesting and hitherto Unex-
      plained phenomenon whioh is often seen daring
      a solar eo'ipse for a few seconds just before
      and just after totality, and that is the appear-
      ance of what are called “aha low bands”’<pas!iiog
      as waves of shadow with greater or lews rapidity
      across the groond or on the fronts of walls
      facing the sun. Although there is, perhaps, no
      greatsoieutifio value to be anticipated from their
      investigation, th-ir very mystcriousnessisasnffi-
      oient reason for their careful observation, and at
      every station at whioh observers are sta-
      tioned they have boon notod, and the follow-
      ing particulars recorded ; tho - direction in
      which the bands lie, the direction in which
      they move,the velocity with whioh they travel,
      tho width of the bands, and of the spaoes
      between them. The object of this investiga-
      tion an attempt to ascertain if they bo
      duo to the effeot of our atmosphere, or to
      anything oonueotod with the eon itself.
      That they are not optioal illusions is proved
      by. the fa-t that they -are nearly always
      seen by several observers and have beeu
      photographed. It is possible they may be a
      phenomenon of diffraction and interferon re
      ooonrring at a time when what is still left of the
      photosphere is beooming a mere po;nt of
      light in the sky, but in either oase their
      motion is, at present, impossible to explain.
      We are not aware of the appearanoe Of any
      of these bands daring tbe eolipse of yesterday,
      bat it is quite possible that later new* from
      our speoial correspondent at Assouan tow
      boar referenoe to them.

            <!--***** End of Page 3 ***** --></div>
            <div type="page" n="4"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="5"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="6"> </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>

﻿
