<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Your name</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-10-01">October 1, 2016</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-09-01">September 1, 1905</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T.
                    1.
                </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement">
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">

            THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, FRIDAY, SEPTEMBER 1, 1G65.

            ENGLAND AND JAPJ

            RENEWED ALLIANCE.
            TAKAHASHf INTERVIEWJ
            London, August 31.
            Reuter’s Agency is informed that a n<
            , Anglo-Japanese arrangement was signed
            Lord Lanadowne and Baron Hayashi on t
            12th inst. It affords mutual guarantees fort
            protection of Anglo-Japanese interests, ev
            if only threatened by a single hostile pov
            and assures the maintenance of the status q
            in the Far East.
            Mr. Takahashi in an interview with Rente
            Agency said that Japan has no less ih
            thirty-five millions sterling untouched
            London, Berlin, and New York. There w
            therefore be no necessity to issue a new loa
            as the available resources of Japan are ami
            for clearing up the war. If Japan contemplat
            l the issue of a new loan it would be to oonvc
            1 ’ previous loans bearing a higher rata of interei
            | but be has not heard that the government b
            any such intention. He believes that a last!
            peace in the Far East will be assured, not or
            as a consequence of the war bnt also
            account of tne new relations between G«
            Britain and Japan.	(Reut>
            St. Petersburg, August 31.
            M. Witte in his telegram to the Ti
            j announcing peace, says : '1 have the honor
            report that Japan has agreed to your daman
            concerning the conditions of peace, whioh v
            [ ' established in strict oonformity to yc
            ..l^esty’s indications. Russia will remain
            ever, as hitherto, a great power in the I
            East.”	(Reuti
            (
            Tokio, August 31.
            The details of peace are still unknown. The
            public regards the termination of the war
            , without demonstration, and the concessions
            made will undoubtedly be bitterly criticised.
            (Reutbr)
            St. Petersburg, August 31.
            The Tsar has telegraphed to General Linie-
            vitch informing him that an armistice has been
            concluded.
            The news of the conclusion of peace has
            been received coldly here.	(Home)
            Paris, August 31.
            , President Lonbet has telegraphed to the
            Tsar his lively congratulations for the great
            event his high wisdom has permitted to be
            accomplished. France as Russia’s ally is glad
            to see a war marked by so many heroic deeds
            terminated by so honorable a peace. (Reuter j
            \ '	London, August 81.
            The papers dwell on Japan’s solid gains.
            The City circles are impressed by the sagacity
            shown in choosing the present moment to end
            the war, in view of the impending commercial
            development of China, in which Japan will be
            the ohief participant. It is pointed out that
            Japan is in less need of finahoial assistance
            than Russia.	]	(Renter j
            «	—— -	^
            Ottawa, August 31.
            The Canadian Government has invited the
            peace envoys to visit the Dominion, f Hauler;
            FIGHTING ^ AT HY8ING OSING.
            »	Tokio, August 81.
            Marshal Oyama reports extensive fighting
            on the 27th instant to the north-east of Hysing
            Using and other places, resulting in the repulse
            of the Russian attacks, and the oapture of
            their positions.	(Reuter j
            RELEASE OF ALGERIAN CHIEF.
            PARIS, August 31.
            The Sultan of Morocco has released the
            Algerian chief The other French demands
            have not yet been conceded.	{Reuter,
            Paris, August 31.
            TW letter of the Moorish government relat
            ing to the release of the Algerian contains'
            termB and reservations which France refuses
            to accept. The incident is therefore unset-
            tled.	(Revt-r
            THE CHANNEL SQUADRON.
            Berlin, August 31.
            The burgomaster of Swinemuende enter-
            tained 120 British bluejackets to supper yes
            terday evening. A party of British officers has
            come here.	*	(Reuterj
            THE SUCRERIE8 SITUATION.
            Paris, Angust 31.
            It is announced that a general meeting of
            tne Sncreriee of Egypt will be held very
            shortly.'	(Bmatj
            CHOLERA TN VT&TTTT.a PUAvrwnr
            — t—	--- isuiuijxi i mjvuivjp
            — <
            Berlin, August 31.	‘
            Germany is taking vigorous steps to cope
            with the feared outbreak of cholera, of which 1
            there have been 12 cases and 6 deaths in thf '
            Vistula Province.	(RmUm \
            - CHOLERA AT HAMBURG. V
            /	ft	j
            Hamburg, August 81.
            There has been a care of cholera here. (F.
            CRICKET CHAMPIONSHIP.
            London, August 81.
            E««ult of County ChampionHhip. Yorkshire
            Hi%8, diawn 7. Lsnoasbire won II, 1
            W*t 8, drawn 10,	( (Reuter} \
            N LOCAL Mi GENERAL.
            Tub Plague.—Yesterday’s bulletin reports
            one death in hospital and four cases onred at
            Alexandria.
            I	,
            . .. •
            DJ, Quarantine.—A telegram from Pera states
            " that arrivals from Damietta are subjected to a'
            medical visit.
            Stray and Ownerless Dogs found in the
            !1. \ Khalifa district of Cairo during to-morrow
            new night and at dawn of the 3rd. inst. will be
            ^ poisoned by the police.
            he	*
            Bn Suez Canal.— 9 vessels passed through the
            er Canal on the 29th inst., of which 3 were British,
            30 9 German, 2 Dutch, 1 French, 1 Russian. The
            .» day’8 receipt were fra. 238,186,08, making the
            ,n' total from the latinst. frs. 8,719,807.14.
            t Bodies in the Nile.—Three dead bodies
            e have been found floating in the Nile near the
            d Kafr el Zayat bridge. Medical examination
            t revealed the fact that death had been caused
            by gunshot wounds. The corpses have not
            0 yet been identified.
            on The Weather at Alexandria.—Although
            eat the temperature at Alexandria is not high for
            'er) the time of year, the weather is exceedingly
            damp. Tuesday’s weather report showed that
            • degree of humidity was higher thaD it had been
            for many mouths, and it still oontinues so.
            ads	*
            rill The El Rouei Affair.—M. Axerio, examin-
            °,nr ing magistrate to the tribunal of the Italian
            consulate, went to the Voronof hospital yester-
            gpj day morning to take the depositions of Kamel
            Effendi Hanein, who was badly wounded in
            . the fight with Italians in the Gamh el Ahmar
            i’he district of Cairo.
            var	■ ■
            Blind Fiki Injured.—Yesterday morning
            an arabieh ran over and severely injured a
            blind fiki named Abdallah Hassanein, who
            lives in the Anfoushy quarter. The accident
            lie- occurred in the Sharia Abu el AbbaB, whence
            sen the injured man was rapidiy conveyed to
            hospital. His injuries are very serious.
            ias	,
            rum I
            Ibrahimieh Casino. —To day being the
            anniversary of the Sultan’s accession, two per-
            formances will be given at the theatre of the
            Crown Casino, Ibrahimieh, the first commen-
            cing at half past four. The evening entertain-
            ment, commencing at half past nine, will
            inolude a ball and a firework display, in addi-
            tion to the ordinary variety performance. The
            programme is exceptionally good, inoluding
            the popular artistes Miles Marie Fleur, Nina
            de Pervenche, Lyda Osman, M. Stephany, eto.
            The French Fete.— The accounts of the
            French National F6te, which was held on the
            14 h ultimo in the Esbekieh Gardens, closed
            with a small balanoe to the oredit side, whioh
            will be made over to the Cairo Sooidtd de Bien-
            faisance Fran;aise.The subscriptions amounted
            to nearly 15,000 francs, but,had it not been for
            the generosity of the Gas Company, who furnish-
            ed all the lighting lor the illumination gra-
            tuitously, there would have been a defioit in
            the amounts instead of a surplus, for the cost
            of this portion of the Kite oould not have been
            less than 3,000 francs.
            Collapse of a Roof.—Last night the roof
            of a house in the Bab Sidra quarter collapsed,
            burying a Copt woman named Mariam bint
            Girgis, wife of a shawish named Ghatas Shar-
            kawi. At the time of the accident the woman
            was sitting with her son aged four years at the
            door of the house. The woman, who is
            enceinte, was extricated from the ddbris by
            the police, and removed to hospital, where
            she is under medical treatment. The child,
            who was injured, has apparently lost his
            senses as a result of the accident, and is quite
            unable to speak.
            QllDUimA JJX1UJL.1DI1 UV/UWJL*. — XX11 uamu)
            Church Magazine announces that the English
            sohool at Shoubra will recommence its
            olasses on October 2. Ibis school, which was
            opened in 1903, is confined entirely to British
            children, and is managed by a British staff, and,
            although applications for the admittance of
            native children are not infrequently made,
            they are invariably refused on that ground.
            There are at present thirty-five'Children in the
            school, and it is hoped that this number will
            increase on the opening of the new term. The
            ordinary course includes instruction in mathe-
            matics, geography, the Eoghsh language aDd
            literature, divinity, singing, drawing, Frenob,
            and Latin, and to these may be added on
            payment of extra fees Arabic, German, and
            music.
            THE DTATE JlvAXIaWAid.— mo luuiwoo ui wjc
            nassenger traffic on the state railways is
            certainly phenomenal when one considers the
            comparative smallness of the country and the
            -onversative habits of its inhabitants, in
            many .districts locomotion by camel or donkey
            being still preferred to stesm. Yet during the
            period from the 1st January to the 10th
            August of this year the augmentation in the
            cumber of persons travelling was approxim-
            ately one and a half millions oompared with
            the same period of 1904, the inorease in the
            receipts under this bead basing L.K. 88,880.
            The goods treffio also increased enormously,
            and the inorease would have been greater had
            the administration the requisite rolling stock
            to cope with it. Notwithstanding this draw-
            back the Government railways carried in
            the period mentioned 521,482 tops more
            merebandiee than last year, with an inoreaae
            of nearly L.E. 88,000 in the receipts from thin
            branch of the eendoe.
            A NATIONAL CONGRESS.
            AMAZING DOCUMENT.
            We have received a species of manifesto,
            3a printed in Cairo and drawn np, we shonld
            a‘ say by some very young men. It is described
            as a circular of the public advocates of a
            National Congress. This congress, we are
            >e assured, has decided to establish a school for
            w young Egyptians anxions to see their country
            progress. It aims at a campaign against dis-
            honesty and self indulgence and especially
            against the vioes that injure social and
            ie family life. The Congress also aims atthe forma-,
            b, tion of a club in Cairo where disoussions can
            ie be held, with the objeot of discovering the
            ie moral needs of the country, and the methods
            whereby Egyptians may be educated and
            enlightened.
            It aims at persnading the natives of the
            68 country to keep the wealth of the country ip
            10 their hands, and so .to condnet themselves that
            m foreigners will cease to look down on them.
            !(* In this way Egyptians will one day govern
            themselves. The Congress proposes to bring
            it* views before the Government in the near
            futnre. Its suggestions can be Bammed np as
            ;h follows.
            ir	i.—Restrictions should be imposed on
            ly European immigrants to Egypt with a view
            it to restricting crime and only admitting persons
            )Q whose antecedents are respeotable and possess
            a certain sum of money.
            2.—Companies shonld be striotly prohibited
            from encroaching on the privileges granted
            Q. them by the Government,
            in 3.—The Regulation of all bourse specula-
            j. tions.
            01	4.—Restrictions should be imposed on ex-
            I	ports and imports, so as to check the excessive
            export of necessaries—such as cereals—and
            ir the consequent rise of their price.
            5.—The establishment of local commissions
            throughout Egypt to regulate the prioe of
            >8 vegetables, bread and meat,
            ft	6.—A thorough inspection of liquor shops.
            10	7.—Rents should not be permitted to rise
            it above a certain leveL
            ie	8.—The 2 % rate levied by the Municipality
            to of Alexandria for the construction of the new
            eea wall to be abolished, the sea-wall being
            now completed.
            9.—The reduction of the salt tax.
            10	10.—The reduction of the rates levied by the
            r' water company.
            10 rlhe authors of this document have refrained
            n‘ from signing their names in full, and we have
            gathered nothing from a study of some rather
            II	cryptic initials. As for their suggestions, some
            3* appear to us to be unnecessary, the attention
            10 of the Government being oocnpied with the
            '8 discovery of the means to combat the evils of
            ia which the signatories complain, while others
            °* are so thoroughly medieval that we cannot
            help being amnsed at the naivetd of the writers,
            ie who obviously imagine that the revival of the
            ie trade restrictions of the fifteenth centnry will
            id prove a panacea for any economic ailments from
            ih which Egypt suffers,
            a-	---------
            NATIVE PRESS COMMENTS.
            The comments of the native Press on the
            Accession day of the Sultan bear a decided
            resemblance to those of Turkish newspapers,
            published on previous occasions of this kind
            at Constantinople, and often quoted as exam-
            ples of what we may call the ‘honorific’ style
            of composition. In reading them we move in
            august regions peopled by courtly superlatives,
            resonant titles and cardinal virtues, in a fairy-
            land of splendour and dignity where debts
            and difficulties are ignored and where the
            Commander of the Faithful and the great
            dignitaries of his ^Empire receive the endless
            homage of a contented people. This species of
            composition cannot perhaps be naturalised in
            Egypt with complete success. We reproduce
            the following extract from our contemporary.
            “Ax Lewa.”
            "Twenty-nine years have passed since H.I.M.
            Sultan Abdnl Hamid II. ascended the throne
            of his illustrious ancestois. Since that date be
            has revived hopes that seemed to have died,
            and has preserved the honor of his kingdom,
            and maintained it in an exalted and honorable
            position, after finding it a prey to disorder
            and threatened by rain. He has smitten down
            with an iron hand the pernicions rebels who
            plotted its rain and has scattered them abroad,
            lie has watched over the development of
            -oienoe and industry, and has opened schools,
            institutes, and colleges in every part of
            his empire, while doing all in his power
            to preserve the old Moslem teaching
            from modern and oontaminatiDg influences
            He has continually striven to protect and
            strengthen the faith and has moreover built
            numerous warships, constructed railways, and
            organised a great and victorious army. If the
            Moslem world oelebrates this ffite, the Turkish
            nation celebrates with it the day of its political
            revival. The committee has therefore organised
            ,11 measures that will make this celebration
            far superior to those of the past in honor of
            tho preservation of our beloved Sultan from
            the scoundrels who reoently attaoked him.
            THIS 1'AJNAJUA UAIMALi.
            w
            Monsieur Quelleneo, who was formerly chief w
            mgineer of tho Suez Canal Company in Egypt
            tnd is now their consulting engineer in Paris, gi
            is at present in the United Slates and will J,
            assist at the International Committee of Engin- rt.
            eers which is to assemble to-day in Washington .
            to determine whether the Panama Canal is to K
            be on the look system or otherwise. Monsieur j*1
            Qneilenneo, as our readers will, remember, was «
            >no of those who was consulted by the Alexan- T
            dria Municipality .and the Government U
            regarding the new quays before any dpoision M
            was taken, and he has been obosen in this
            instance by the Government of. the United
            States on account of bip long association with
            the works of improvements undertaken for
            some years on the Sue* Oanal^wbioh rote
            carried oat under bis direction. Two Ftonoh
            men are to sit on the oommittoe, th<p, other «
            being Monsieur Godard, inspector general of hi
            the ponts ot ohnnwds in Pens.'	IH
            7 jEGYPTIACA.
            BY JOSEPH OFFORD.
            The new association founded in Haris
            somewhat npon the model of the British,
            Egyptian, and Palestine Exploration Fonda,
            the “Socidt^ Fran^aise de Fouilles Arohdologi-
            ques,” has recently held an exhibition at the
            Petit-Palais de Champs Elysdes, in whioh were
            shown the results of M. A. Gayet’s latest
            campaign of excavations at Antinoe.
            As is well known this explorer has been
            working at the site of the Emperor Hadrian’s
            celebrated oity at various times since 1896,
            bat no season’s explorations have been so fruit-
            ful as the last. Hitherto M. Gayet had
            devoted his attention to the vast necropolis
            to the north-east of the town, bnt this oeme-
            tery did not possess tombs of the rioher or
            patrician families, though those of various
            pagan and Christian people were touqd there
            of what. may be termed well-to-do people.
            The great men, however, of the capital of the
            Roman Thebaid were undiscovered, and so this
            last winter M. Gayet searched in the rocky
            valleys on the edge of the “Arabian Plateau”
            toward the Red Sea, and was rewarded by find-
            ing a superior style of sepulchres, though most
            of them had been pillaged, probably in late
            Persian times under Chosroes, about A.D. 600.
            The description of the tomb given by the
            Gayet in the “Catalogue Sommaire” of the
            Exhibition neednot detain uahereexoeptingthe
            aooonnt of one, the banal arrangement of which
            was so nniqne that it is interesting to read the
            explorer’s description in fulL "L’nn d’eux, oh je
            retrouvais le corps d’un gladiateur.offrait oette
            particularity caractdristique que, sur tout le
            fond, nne dpaisse couche de ciment reoouvnit
            les dalles. Une silhouette humaiue y avait dtd
            modelde eu creux, donnant de profit les ligues
            d’ensemble du squelette, auquel s’aoorochaient
            les masses figurant le vgtement. Les cdtes, les
            os des bras, des jam bee, dtaient dessirds aveo
            soin ; k l’entonr, les lignes dn rappel de man-
            teau ytaient en proportion snffisante. Autre
            detail non moins important: alors que dans
            toutes les tombes le mort repose conchy sur le
            dos, le corps dn gladiatenr ytait y tend a sur le
            c6W, s’emboitant dans ce monlage, bien qn’il
            fftt un tiers environ pins grand que nature.
            C’est le seul exemple jnsqn’iei de pareil fait
            observy.”
            The Gayet notes the valuable fact that in
            Christian burials the mummy holds in his
            right hand upon the breast the “crown of
            election” just as in early and late Egyptian
            tomb3 the deceased grasped the magic sceptre,
            Nek, whioh symbolised the future life in the
            theology of the anoient priests. Also the
            presence of portraits in all the tombs ot
            wealthy people is connected evidently with
            the portraits, from the "Double” or “Ka” spirit
            in the old Egyptian sepulchres, whioh in
            the latter were mostly statues and not relief
            representation of the defnnot The same idea
            that if the mummy were destroyed, the replica
            or effigy would take its place appears to have
            lingered on into Christian times. The custom of
            gilding the face, fully dwelt upon in the
            “Egyptian Gazette” in an essay entitled “The
            Golden Horns,’’was still practised qhite late'y
            at Antinoe, reminding ns of the Pharaonic reli-
            gious literature, promising the deceased should
            have a “visage shining as the light,or “that
            the eyes shall see the light.” To ensure the
            fulfilment of this latter formula, the mummies
            in some cases have little rolls of bitumen
            covered with gold leaf, inserted in the orbital
            sockets.
            Among the tombs discovered, the most inter-
            esting occupants were a charioteer andagladia-
            tor,doubtless celebrated champiousin theoircus
            fetes at Antinoe and a lady “Khelmis” the
            famous singer of Osiris Antinons, certainly a
            priestly hierophant in the temple wherein the
            unfortunate favorite of Hadrian was worshipped
            under the oeremonial cult of the ancient
            Egyptian rituaL Other frames appear also to
            have been those of aotors in the Antinoe
            Olympic games, or of offioiants in the "Mys-
            teries” instituted in honor of the lovely youth
            Antinons.
            (To be continued.)
            VITALITY STATISTICS.	ftutl
            ---------	wen
            From the latest returns of the statistical sect
            office in Cairo we find that the births regis-
            tered there during the week ending Saturday com
            19th August, were 410, inoludiDg 3 of Euro- tiop,
            pean parentage; and the week following 441,	"
            which included 6 of the latter category. For out
            the two weeks under review the deaths were ^l0
            492, of which 9 were of European nationa-
            lity, and 489, of these 19 being Europeans,
            During the same weekly periods the total mB1
            number of births at Alexandra were 271, of t0re
            which 12 were of European parentage; and 255,
            including 6 of the latter category. The deaths
            totalled 233 for the first week, of which 17 —
            wore Europeans; and 256, in the second
            week, including 19 of the latter.
            It should be remarked that the figures
            given relating to the births of European ohil- 0 al
            dren are th so sent in by the district in-
            xpeotors, as the new law compelling the re- ,	,
            filtration of all children belonging to Europeans ^
            does not come into operation until it has 1 a
            been approved of by the International Mixed n>e<1
            Tribunals, and therefore the retorns are apt to ?en'
            be mUleading. Buoh, however^ is not the case <n*.
            as regards the mortality statistic*. '	. *?)0.
            ——------ V.,.	aU
            STEAMER MOVEMENTS.
            ana
            *	,	f..	u cfjj
            The Ellerman S.S. Britannia left Liverpool of ti
            for Alexandria direct on Thursday and is die Hpi
            here on the llth inst. with gen end outgo end fron
            passengers.	| wbl
            * i	k
            for
            THE CONGO FREE STATE.
            '
            OFFTnTAL nnMMmiinATirhxr
            „ ,2“
            Mr. E. D. Morel, r hon. secretary of the
            Congo Reform ' Association, has iaened for
            publication the farther correspondence that
            has passed between his organisation and Lord
            L&nsdowne, the Secretary fir Foreign Affairs.
            Lord Lansdowne’s communication, whioh is
            dated the 17th inst., is a reply to One from Mr.
            Morel on the 8th inst., respecting the native
            witnesses, and it is in the following terms:
            "I am to inform you that reports of the
            privations from whioh these natives are suffer-
            ing have been received through the acting
            British Consul at Boma, and his Majesty’s
            Minister at Brussels has been fristfneted to (ill
            the attention of the Congo Government to the
            matter.
            “I am to state that the latter recently point- ]
            ed ont to Monsieur de Cavelier, in the oonne ani
            of conversation, the hardship involved by send- an
            ing considerable, numbers of native witnesses,
            required in connection with the trial of white
            men, to Boma from the Upper Congo, and
            inquired whether such trials oonld not jei
            place in the Upper Congo. Monsieur de Cave- ?l
            lier replied that the practice cf holding tijala,
            when white man were involve^, in the Upper
            Congo or rather remote distriots, had, since g‘
            1895, in conseqnenoe of the Stokes case, been 7T
            abaadoned. and that it would require serious g
            consideration whether it would he possible to 01
            resume the praotioe of holding trade, of as
            important a character as those now under
            disoussion anywhere bnt atthe principal seat of ws
            justice.	in
            “I am to add th&t his Majesty’s Acting
            Consul at Boma has been instructed to give
            the D&tive witnesses such assistance as he
            properly oan in their efforts to obtain work
            during their detention at Boma.”	P3*
            Mr. Morel, as a rejoinder, submitted the
            following to Lord Lansdowne :
            “In the report to the Sovereign of the Qj
            State (‘Rapport an Roi-Souverain’), dated ^
            Brussels, 21st May, 1897 (‘Bulletin Official
            No. 5 bis, numero aupplementaire’), it ia ^
            stated:
            In all the districts of the interior the
            creation of territorial tribunals has been ,
            decided, empowered to apply penal law to ac
            ail residents in the State, native, or other, _
            the courts-martial thus becoming com-
            petent only to deal with military eases.
            “It is true that in the same official report
            the value of the new organisation was greatly p.
            lessened by the proviso that in cases of ‘murder
            and homioide,’ and of ‘attempts npon the life
            or liberty of the natives’ (the charges brought
            against Europeans employed in the Upper
            Congo, for the prompt local investigation of ^
            whioh the machinery referred to in the pro- t0.
            vious paseages of the report was ostensibly
            created, being precisely of this character) the
            Europeans accused should be brought before
            the Tribunal in'the Lower Congo, the objeot by
            being, as stated in the report, ‘to guarantee 00
            more efficaciously the repression of particular-
            ly grave aots.’ Bat the procedure adopted in
            v*rions oases would appear to differ not a
            little. Thus on November i4th, 1901, M.
            Lejeune, an agent of the A.B.I.R. Society,
            was sentenced by the Territorial Tribunal at
            Coquilhatville—,whioh, aooording to Monsieur
            de Cuvelier, would appear to be non-existent gt
            —to six months’ imprisonment, and 1,000 fri>. „
            fine. The original charges in this ease would U
            seem to have been those of making war npon
            the natives without authorisation, in the tb
            oourse of whioh the bodies of the slain were
            alleged to have had their hands removed ;
            and handing out firearms to soldiers oontrary •
            to law. M. Lejeune, I understand, was so- 1U
            quitted of the first-named oharges by the looal
            tribunal, apd acquitted of the latter on appeal.
            “Whatever arguments may be adduced by
            Monsieur de Cuvelier in explanation of the
            present system of administering justice in the
            Congo, the resultant effect is, on the one hpud,
            to facilitate the escape of Europeans involved „
            in alleged oases of atrocity ; on the other, p
            to bring unmerited sufferings upon native wit- 6
            nesses, and to close the months of native
            witnesses who would be only too anxious to
            come forward to testify to the wrongs of whioh n
            they and their relatives have been, apd con- w
            tinue to be, the victims, were local courts 1
            authorised to deal with their grievances and
            were they guaranteed from subsequent per- p,
            secntioD.	t;	Vf
            “The present system, in its praotical out- “
            come, constitutes, indeed, a negation of jus-
            tics, and admits of no defence.	r	*1
            “In conclusion, I would bsg leave to point
            out reapeotfully to your lordship that, while Mi
            the ‘oareful regulations’ indicated by Monsieur
            de Cuvelier are beiDg e’aborafed, and while 0-
            the report of the Commission of Inquiry re-
            mains still unpublished, the slaughter and tor- Ca
            tare of natives in the Upper Congo oontinne
            with monotonous persistency.
            J
            itish Chamber of,Commerce.—We would Nal
            the attention of manufacturers and mer- Neg
            n to the work of the British Chamber of Goa
            nerce of Egypt, whioh was formed ir Mm
            with the sole objeot of assisting British Brdi
            in this ooontry. The servioes ttf the
            iber are always at the disposal of any
            jer desiring information on trade m^ttera Bmi
            ally, inoluding the question of appoint- i f
            nitable agents. As no fre is obarged for
            advioe, it {■ obvjpusly in tty intereataof
            ntiah traders here to beoome members, I lint
            ft	i"
            35
            s enwifY*	Mel
            m
            •-	3 *
            tam ’mimtkL
            9
            Ate-AAV * - , - *-£**••* «*>». v U- *
            S" ”	> expected tfr leave
            i -tor Constantinople oo Thursday or
            f.
            II Jua cam--	1!.	DC
            CttJokahaakJVha an*Mm. Go«k
            T**	from j iMtfMtl)**. fcen&vpt on the
            'he 29th instant by the P.&O. Persia.
            Mr Pi,.„	a**,•**.•>«n«iebi
            towns mid GoJmnment	j,
            to return to Cairo on or aboutthe loth inst.
            g , ChittY Bov dfrMbtr^aJ^Lj*’
            uuiy qireotor jeneral ot,.eiuit(i«s,
            whioh u due at Port Said on tlae 18^mat
            Mr. H. Carter Wil^n/^irector of DMonnel
            and accounts to the Ministry of the*Inlerior
            arrived a't Alexandria from Cairo yesterday.
            leaving Marseilles by the P &O. Persia on th*
            29th inst
            Sues Canal police, will return from leave oh
            uie 4th Ootober and resume his duties at Port
            Said,
            -4	. m"^~^"***
            Mr. Astley P. Friend director of tpe Cain)
            waterworks, is expected back from England
            in the 10th inst
            1	# t
            Mr. Douglas Morice returns to Cairo oa tee
            20th mat. and resumes his duties at district
            postal inspector. -**
            u	jwangaau ont .
            v	*otin*	va0«t iqt
            Greece, has amrad n	»;H
            aka part in the official huwu#t: ©veu-hy the
            legent thu evening'in honor of the dnltan’s
            icoession,
            Mirza Ali Asghar Khan, diplomatic agent
            md consul-general for Persia, arrived at Alex-
            andria to-day.
            -.•-■■a. ,
            M. D. Zeppa, the Italian wiunwi—loiiei sited
            Jaisse de laDerte, bus strived at Alexaadria
            rnd will take part in to night’s offioial banquet.
            M- P88^?00	,duootor««oertl of
            the Cairo Tramways Company,returns to Cairo
            to-day.	t,
            Dr. and Mrs. Bentley are tearing London
            by the P.&O. Arabia and will arrive in Cairo
            !>n the 20th iost
            t
            .......... •<»>.•!' -»•* .
            Mr. John Cafflari will leave Alexandria next
            Friday by the Messageries steamer, on his way
            to London.
            Mr. B. Gon^.who uhtil reoently ohief oi the
            Stocks and Shares department
            Jttoma^ .^ank at Cai^ has appointed
            mb manager of th9 Alexand ia branoh of
            the Bank of Salonioa.
            Mr. and Mrs. Soott-Dalgieish will he hack
            in Cairo on the 4th proximo.
            (.	'Vh	. atitiiHk C*»3
            PAI81VOIR Lilt.
            . A R RIVALS.- -	.
            The followiig passengers arrived at Port
            Said on the 29‘h ulto. per P. and 0. 8.8.
            Persia:	1 , J \	' -
            Mr. B. L' Haslett and Mr. Dodison.
            Arrived from London per P; & O. 8.8. Bri-
            t&ntiia : —Mrr O. Graham. MrtvBewley, Mr.
            D. Seymour,, Mr,,and,McKay Mr. G.
            Malcombe, Mr, C. H. Lowenthal. ^
            From Marseille*
            Capt> Goldsmith, Mr. J. J. Jelf Mr. H. S.
            Philpotts, Mr. M. A. Slater, Mr. F. Jaoqnes,
            Mr, W, Henijiy, Mr, Sinado, .Mr. if. Kemaid,
            Capt. Scmervill*, Q«*,t, P. Wood, QapL R. B.
            Blalreneyt Mff Man? field, Mr. and Mrs. Man*
            «nd three children, Mr. J. Fenett, Mr.P.
            Martina.
            Arrived at Port Said from Brindisi per P. &
            0. 8.S. Osiris, 80th olto.iAl r. n i^,.* UJU
            Miss A. Young, Mr. I. Rale; Mr. H. Walsh,
            Capt. Satterley.
            DEPARTURES.	■	. *■
            jepaqnebot Sirin, dela Ole Florto Rubat-
            ) parti hier pour Gineaavait fc hrtd i.'
            UM. L Matranga, A. FWlSira, OUNMhlei, 0.
            hum, Di Benedetto; Naha*, R A»ArtuMa> B.
            grist safille, M. et Mme ROmeiap Mil*
            islati, Roeemberg, Dr Spoer el ftau^M. St
            ie A. Foly, P. Canoaioi, 0. & WuteteipP.
            omen et fils, Mile Birell etrlwm^ Ales
            drini, Touche « frm., 'IWtedteiMtef; Y.
            id	^
            neilta^tS
            4r. Alrx.	Pro^Bamuteterm
            J. M Lansing antf\4«Q|htor, Mr. Hertol,
            I. BoHhadten, Mr. 0, 0. L^rte lte Wm.
            bmi Mr R Arsuteirt, Mr f
            . Bdgar Kirby, Mr. Y. Levy*. Mr. Cteatet
            hum,	‘
            *	’ '-'5^ ■-: 1


            <!-- ***** END OF PAGE 3 ***** --></div>
            <div type="page" n="4"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="5"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="6"> </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>



﻿
