<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Your name</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-29">September 29, 2016</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
<!-- **Add Issue Date**-->                    <date when="1905-01-01">Enter issue date</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, WEDNESDAY, AUGUST 30, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T.
                    1.
                </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement">
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
            THI EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, WEDNESDAY, AUGUST 3O, 1905,

            PEACE AT LAST.
            JAPAN'S magnanimity.
            'w*
            Plaqde Credits. — The Sanitary Admini
            stration has demanded a new eredit of L.E.
            10,000 for measures against the plague.
            IMPORTANT POINTS CEDID.
            t
            San Stefano Casino.—A grand night fete
            will be held at San Stefano Casino next Satur-
            day, when there will bo a display of fireworks.
            WORLD-WIDE EXCITEMENT.
            , Portsmouth (N.H.), August 29.
            It is understood that as a result of yester-
            day’s Council at Tokio, Baron Kamnra will
            submit to M Witte a new basis for a compro-
            mise	f Renter)
            Woman Scalded.— An Arab woman Darned
            ' jatifa bint Girgis fell yesterday while carrying
            a kettle full of boiling water on her head. She
            was severely scalded and will require fifteen
            days’ treatment.
            Portsmouth (N.H.), August 29.
            The Conference has arrived at a complete
            agreement on all questions, and decided to
            proceed with the elaboration of a treaty.
            (Later). Japan yielded all the outstanding
            questions and accepted the Russian proposal
            that there should be no indemnity, and that
            Saghalien should be divided without the
            payment of any redemption money. She with-
            drew Articles X. and XL of the original peace
            proposals relative to the surrender of the
            interned warships and the limitation of, the
            \ Russian naval power in the Far East. An
            armistice will probably be arranged this after-
            noon.	(Renter)
            The Plaque.—A Greek groom from a stable
            in the Labban quarter, Alexandria, was yester-
            day admitted into hospi a1, suffering from
            Dubonic plague. One death in hospital and one
            recovery is also recorded from Alexandria.
            Fayoum-Light Railways.—The.receipts of
            the Fayonm Light Railways Company for the
            ten days from 11th to 20th August amount
            to L.E. 620.062, this beiDg an increase of L.E.
            50.648 over the corresponding period of last
            year.
            London, August 29.
            The news of an agreement spread like
            wild fire and caused the most intense excite-
            ment here and in New York. The magnanimity
            of, Japan Las produced a profound impression.
            \	{Renter)
            Portsmouth (U.8.A.), August 29.
            'The Japanese have accepted the Rnssian
            ultimatum ; no indemnity, and division of
            Saghalien without re purchase payment. They
            have also yielded on the question of interned
            vessels, and npon the limitation oi the Rnssian
            navy in the Far East.	(Ifaval)
            New York, August 29.
            The peace conference has arrived at a
            complete agreement. Peace is arranged. (B.)
            THE CHANNEL SQUADRON.
            The Windsor Hotel — A cinematograph
            entertainment will be given at the Windsor
            lotel this evening by Mr. E. Fuller, who has
            an excellent apparatus and a very varied
            selection of films, so that the audience can be
            sure of spending an enjoyable evening. The
            entertainment will commence at 9.30 p.m.
            GERMAN PRESS COMMENTS.
            Berlin, August 29.
            The press devotes many columns to the
            description of the Channel Squadron. The tone
            is friendly sr.d satisfaction is expressed at the
            meeting of the British and German fleets. (B.)
            PERSONAL AND SOCIAL.
            Harvey Pasha arrived yesterday at Alex-
            andria by the evening train.
            Ismail Pasha Sabri, under secretary of state
            to the Ministry of Justice, arrived yesterday
            from Cairo at 1 p.m.
            Major Johnstone, president of the State
            Railways, left on Monday for Upper Egypt and
            is expected back in Cairo on Friday.
            -----k----.
            Captain C. H. G. Garratt, A. P. D., has been
            granted leave of absence from Ootober 5 to
            November 23.
            Mr. Thomas McPherson, inspector of
            masonry, and Mr. David 0. F. Watt, draughts-
            man at the Assouan Reservoir, have been
            granted three months leave of absence to date
            from the 1st instant.
            Dr. Gumprecht,’ the Gentian Consul, at
            Cairo, is shortly going on leave for three
            months and during his absence the aoting-
            Consnl will be M. von Verson, the German
            Consul at Saltnica, who is expected in Cairo
            next week.
            The offices of the Soofefe Gdndrale des Su-
            creries were closed on Tuesday as a mark of
            respect for the memory of the late M. Cros-
            rfier, president of the company, who died in
            Paris on f Monday last.
            M. Foaden, the Secretary of the Khedivia
            Agricultural Society, has retnrned.to Cairo and
            has resumed his functions.
            \
            Mr. Diomedes Sarakomenos, who has been.
            ajipointed director of agricnltore in Cyprus
            has taken up the duties of his new office. Mr
            Sarakomenos was for many years professor oi
            natural science in the Gymnasia and * sob-
            director of the School of Agriculture, Atbenp,
            and for seven years has been direotor of the
            Missolongbi and Corfu agricultural stations.
            He holds the diplomas of the Institut Agreno-
            mique de Paris, and of the Academie des
            Sciences (Sorbomie) Paris.
            WINDSOR HOTEL Restaurant
            Table tf'Hate Luncheons & Dinners
            Served en the Terrace.
            CRCBB6TBA PLATS 6 TO 11.80 P.M
            piusiiiu *»* renew im mmr,
            ,0CAL AND GENERAL.
            Gun Accident.—A French lid was play-
            ing with a gun yesterday in Moharrem Bey
            qnarter, when the weapon went off and injured
            lie sister, a little girl of eight years of age,
            who will be for at least twelve days in the
            doctor’s hands.
            Drowned in tiie Harbour —A lighter
            aden with stones caps’z id in the harbour
            yesterday. Of the crew of four, three were
            rescued, the fourth, a native named Abd el
            Aziz was drowned. His body has not yet been
            recovered.
            Suez Canal.—25 vessels passed through
            the CaDal on the 26th ar.d 27th inst., 13 of
            which were Brit'sh, 7 German, 1 Italian, 2
            frenob, 1 Spanish, 1 Norwegian. The receipts
            Tor the two days were frs. 789,387.78, making
            the total from the 1st. inst. frs. 8,108,880.57.
            Army of Occupation.—During the absenoe
            of Brigadier-General G. M. Bollock C.B., in
            Cyprus and Crete, the command of the Forces
            in Egypt will be assumed by Colonel F. W. N.
            IfacCraoken, D.S.O., Royal Berkshire Regiment,
            and that of the troops in Cairo by Lieut.-Col.
            I, C. C. Cox, Royal Inniskilling Fusiliers.
            Incident on the Quays.—We are informed
            to-day that in the incident to which—owing
            to the nature of the report translated from the
            Arabio whioh was given ns—we referred under
            the heading “an insistent woman,” a lady of
            great literary ability and social distinction was
            involved. A version of the affair, differing from
            that which we received yesterday, has been
            handed in the form of a complaint to H.B.M.’s
            Consulate. The case being sub jndice we pro-
            pose to abstain from all comment until the
            conclusion of the enquiry.
            A Drastic Remedy.—A native of Cairo,
            who has a great liking for any form of alcohol,
            indulged, we are told, too freely on Tuesday
            evening, and on returning home after hip
            carousal, sank into a drunken slumber. His
            two sons, who had long deplored their father’s
            proclivities, bethought themselves cf a certain
            cure, and promptly pht their idea into praotice
            by setting his beard and whiskers on fire. We
            trust that these two men will receive a severe
            pnnishmeDt, fob, whatever their intention, thtf
            act was exceedingly brutal.
            The El Rouei Affray.—The condition of
            Kamel Effendi Henein, of the seoret police,
            who was shot in the affray which we have
            already mentioned, shows a marked improve-
            ment. Further investigations by the polioe
            have proved that the Italians implicated in
            the affair were members of a band of thieves.
            Their headquarters in the Gamh el Ahmar
            quarter has been found to oontain a large
            quantity of stolen silks, jewellery and other
            valuables which have mysteriously disappear-
            ed from various shops and honses. It is hopei
            that the rest of the band will soon be captured.
            PASSENGER LIST.
            ARRIVALS.
            Le paquebot Sirio, de la Cie Florio Rubat-
            tino arrive avant-hier de G&nes avait b bord :
            MM. Catefsgo, A. Kroner, 0 Conegliano,
            Perpz, T. Sutello, M. et Mme Galves, F. Grosso,
            Riccardo, Faranda, Talama, G. Ardizzone, M.
            et Mme Nello, Di Grande, M. Deebay, Rdes
            soeurs Raobele et Valeri, tog. Principe, M-et
            Mme Azzopardi, Mattei, E. d’Amelio, Ant,
            Zahar, Greoh et fils, A. Grech, L. Roberto, cap.
            A. Bianobi, Eugenia Cardooci, Baoigalupo et
            fern., L Conradi, D. Chiapponi, Haupt, Katz
            Hans, M. et Mme A. Aldo, L Siri, Frizzi et
            fsro., prof. Pace, A. Bruno, S. Lambert), G.
            Constmecn, B. Granelli, 0. Paccofi, M. Mas-
            aolli, L. Fallottj et 40 pawagen de Sue olaeie.
            * the news of peace.
            NEWSPAPER PROSECUTION.
            THE WAR AND ITS RESULTS.
            We need not say that the news that peaoe
            >etween the two great Eastern Empires is a
            certainty at last has caused immense satis-
            action in every capital and not least in
            xradon, where the fact that the (Japanese
            alliance had been renewed, if not strengthened,
            w3a hound to render the continuance of a
            singularly desperate sanguinary struggle a
            source of pain to an allied people, united
            moreover to the ally of Japan’s foe by the ties
            of a cordial and generous friendship. The war
            that has jnst ended has been, without question,
            the most stubbornly fought encounter between
            two oivilised nations that has taken place since
            the Napoleonic struggles. Less protracted and
            therefore less bloody than the Amerioan Civil
            War, it was fought by trained armies far better
            equipped and organised than any of the vol-
            unteer forces that took part in the earlier years
            of the great. struggle. It was waged with an
            indifference to loss, a dogged and persistent
            courage that has never been excelled in war.
            The Japanese watchword — “reinforce and
            attack again”—held good in the faoe of every
            repulse, and, if the series of defeats whioh
            ! lussia had to sustain has led some to hold a
            ow opinion of the value of their army, it must
            be remembered that the Tsar’s soldiers, if often
            lieaten, were never routed, and that the care-
            essness and Degleot of too many of their offioers
            was atoned tor by the amazing persistence
            and resolution of the N.C.O.’a and men ,who
            showed the same dogged and unyielding oour-
            age that the Moojik has ever displayed on the
            lattlefield, the spirit that minimised the oon-
            sequences of deteat at Zorndorf and Borodino,
            and ensured victory at Poltava and the Shipka
            ] }ass. On the other side the Japanese have
            given proof that they possess the highest mili-
            tary qualities. An unyielding conrage that
            would not admit a repulse, a fervent and eelf-
            sscrificirg patriotism that made death prefer-
            able to surrender, joined to a thorough and
            scientific preparation for war, have proved them
            the most terrible opponents in the held and the
            most valuable allies. It has been said that the
            Japanese has not yet been tried by the test of
            defeat; surely an army that hurled itself for
            months against the forts of Port Arthur suffer-
            ing horrible loss without a glimmer of success,
            would rot easily be discouraged by defeat in
            the field, and what praise can be too high for
            Admiral Togo, who, after losing two out of his
            six battleships.and one'of his fastest cruisers by
            mines or collision in a single afternoon, watoh-
            ed Port Arthur and its six blockaded battle-
            ships with nndiminished vigilance, and finally
            crippled the hostile fleet in the great battle of
            August 10, 1904 without the loss of a single
            vessel 1
            To turn to the results 6f the war, Japan is
            eft supreme in Korea and Liao tung, the Man-
            churian railway south of Kharbin reverts to
            China, and Japan obtains useful fishing rights
            on the Siberian coast. The questions of the
            indemnity and of the interned war-ships are
            waived altogether. The 8&ghalien dispute is
            settled by a compromise, the southern half of
            the island reverts to the Japanese, to whom
            it originally belonged,while Russia regains the
            northern half just wrested from her in a brief
            and brilliant campaign by two Japanese reserve
            divisions. So much for the results of the war
            from a mftteriftl point of view.
            -Criticism of the Japanese attitude in accep-
            ing the Rnssian refusal to pay an indemnity
            or to surrender more than half Saghalien
            wonld he ill-timed till the facts are known.
            Japan may have been $oo magnanimous or
            she may have suffered more from the war than
            is generally supposed, but, in our opinion, her
            attitude is probably due to the renewal of
            the Anglo-Japanese alliance on a broader basis,
            whioh guarantees her against attack from any
            quarter, for a period during whioh she can
            recover from the economic disturbances caused
            by the war. In any case criticisms of the peace
            terms may well be left to the morrow. The
            war has ended, the butcheries of Port Arthur
            and the Shaho will not be repeated, and the
            glory of the “Rising Sun" htu suffered no
            eclipse.
            “EL MOAYAD” AND “EL SAYBKA.”
            We have already mentioned that Sheik Ali
            Ynssef, the proprietor and editor of the
            “Moay&d" had brought a charge of attempt at
            blackmailing against Ahmed Fouad, the editor
            of the T S&yeka,” or the "'ITiunderer,” a paper
            published in Cairo, and of a similar nature to
            “La Justioe,” the proprietor of which, Leon
            ?ehmi, was reoently sentenced to one year’s
            imprisonment on a charge of the same descrip-
            tion. It seems that Ahmed Fonad had publish-
            ed some scurrilous artioles in his paper
            regarding the elopement and seoret marriage ot
            Sheikh Ali Yussef with the daughter^ Sheik
            ! SI Saadat (which caused such a sensation and
            so much talk in native ciroles last year) on
            the former refusing to pay hinp £20T;1.
            The tribunal of 8ai'da Zenab has now an-thor-
            ised the Parquet to detain the aocused in
            prison provisionally for a fortnight, whilst the
            neoessary evidence is being got ready for the
            forthcoming trial before the Assize Court now
            Bitting in Cairo. Meanwhile the Parquet is
            examining the witnesses for both sides.
            ARMY OF OCCUPATION.
            COMING CHANGES.
            The following changes will take place daring
            the forthcoming relief season.
            The 2nd battalion Rifle Brigade now station-
            ed at Khartoum and at the Citadel in Cairo
            will embark for India about the third week in
            November. The Royal Berkshire Regiment at
            * lexandria, which arrived here from Sonth
            Africa on 30th November, 1902, will relieve the
            above battalion, and its plaoe will be taken
            by 1st Royal Dublin Fusiliers, which arrive
            from Malta in three detaohments, the first in
            September and the last in November. The
            Royal Inniskilling Fasiliers, now atKasr-el-Ni
            barracks, will send three companies to Crete
            and one oompany to Cyprus, and the four
            companies of the Kings Royal Rifles Corps
            at present serving in those two islands wil
            rejoin the headquarters of the battalion at
            Abbassieh.
            As we have already mentioned the Trans-
            port Assaye, which sails from Southampton
            on the 8th November, will briDg oat the last
            detaobment of the Royal Dublin Fusiliers
            from Malta and embark the Rifle Brigade
            at Suez for India, where it will be stationed at
            Chambatta.
            STEAMER MOVEMENTS.
            .The Khedivial mail steamship Minieh wil
            leave Alexandria at 4 p m. on Saturday anc
            Port Said at 4 p.m. on Sunday for Beyront,
            Tripoli, Minis*, Alex*ndretta,Caiffa and Jaffa.
            NOTES FROM PORT SAID.
            THE ECLIPSE.
            Mr. Smyrnoff. the Diplomatic Agent for
            Russia, Count Antoine Standinoki, Secretary of
            Legation of the Austro-Hungarian Diplomatic
            Agency, Count Arrivabene Gonzaga, the
            acting Diplomatic Agent for Italy, and Mr.
            Roman d’Ertbner, Secretary of the Belgian
            Consulate-General, left Cairo on Monday for
            Assouan to observe the sun’s eclipse of to-day
            and furnish reports to their respective Go-
            vernments.
            Mr. Mitchell Innes, Under-Secretary of
            State, Ministiy of Finance, has invited the
            members of the various commissions to dine
            with him at the Savoy Hotel, Assouan this
            evening. •	'
            SULTAN’S ACCESSION FETES.
            Great preparations are being made for the
            fete whioh is to be held on Saturday night *t
            the Esbekieh Gardens in oelebration of the
            anniversary of H.M. (he Sultan’s Accession.
            A fine arch is being erected at the main
            entranoe to the gardens opposite the Boulao
            avenue, and amongst the numerous amuse-
            ments will be a representation of the play
            Saladin at the Esbekieh theatre, songs by the
            most celebrated native artistes of the day,
            instrumental music, and fireworks. The com-
            mittee have kindly invited all ranks, of the
            Egyptian Army and the Army of Occupation,
            to attend the fete in uniform.
            We are requested to publish the following
            farther list of subscriptions:—Mme. Khonlonsi
            Pasha 750 frs., H.H. Prince Omar Pasha Tous-
            soum 250 tra.; H.E. Mansoor Pasha Yaken
            250 frs. ; H.E. Osman Pasha Galib 500 fra. ;
            HE. Ynssef Pasha Talaat 250 fra.; H.E.
            Abdel Hamid Pasha Sadik 250 fra. ; H.E
            Hussein Pasha Shahin 250 fra.; Ottoman Bank
            50 frs.; M. Mayer 50 frs.; M. Sussman 25 fra. ;
            M. Stein 25 frs. ; M. Daff 25 fra.; previously
            acknowledged 7,500 fra. ; total 10,175 fra.
            FRENCH TORPEDO CRAFT.
            (Fbom our Correspondent.)
            Port Said, Tuesday,
            The torpedo transport Foudre, having on
            board several small harbour defence torpedo
            boats, and also two of the latest submarines,
            and accompanied by one torpedo destroyer,
            and six sea-going torpedo boats, arrived
            here on Sunday en route from Bizerta to
            Djihuti and Saigon. The Bquadron is com-
            manded by Capitaine de vaisseau Niool and
            reports a fair passage. It leaves on Saturday.
            * *
            The Frenoh squadron now at Port Said is
            composed of the following craft:—
            The torpedo depdt ship Foudre, a vessel
            built on much the same lines as H. M. S.
            Vuloan. Displacing 6,036 tons the Foudre is
            capable of a speed of over 19 knots, and carries
            four 8.9 Q. F. guns, four 9-pr Q. F. and four
            i 3 pr Hotchkiss guns. She can carry no less
            than six torpedo vedette boats if required,
            and is at present taking out two submarines
            to strengthen the Frenoh forces in the Far
            East.
            The two submarines are of a new type de-
            signed by M. Romazotti. They are named the
            Perle and the Estnrgeon, carry fonr torpedo
            tubes and displace 68 tons. Their speed does
            not exceed eight knots, bnt they will |m most
            useful vessels if called upon to play a defensive
            role.
            The destroyer Rapifere was launched at
            Rochefort in 1901 and did 28 knots, one knot
            over her estimated speed, at her trials. She
            displaces 303 tons and is armed with one 9-pr.
            Q.F. andsix3-prs. The six torpedo boats whioh
            are to be convoyed to Saigon by. the ‘Foudre’
            are numbered 255, 284, 285, 286, 291 and 292.
            Their displacement varies from 87 to 90 tons.
            Bnilt for a speed of 25 knots they have .all
            done from 25 £ to 27 knots on their trials.
            Each carries two one-pounder antomatio. guns
            and two torpedo tubes, one on a turntable aft
            and one fixed in the bows. Altogether the
            little squadron will greatly inorease the defen-
            sive strength cf the Far Eastern Colonies of
            the Republic.	s;	. «
            THE GARDNER-BROWN COMPANY.
            This oompany started on Monday at the
            Khedivial Theatre a series of what should
            prove to be most successful evenings. '
            A packed house witnessed a lengthy and
            most amusing variety entertainment whioh
            lasted till a late hour.
            Renderings of “Please give me heaven" and
            ''Bluebell” called for much applause, and alto*
            gather the Khedivial management is to be
            congratulated on the entertainment which they
            are providing for their supporters.
            BRITISH BATTLESHIP. •
            H.M.S. Glory, the last of the battleship
            squadron in the China Sea, after a quick ran
            through the Canal, arrived here to-day, and is
            to stay only a short time before proceeding to
            | England. She is one of the newest of her
            I type and carries a orew of 700 men.
            THE CIGARETTE INDUSTRY.
            THE MURDER OF AN OMDEH.
            A NEW DEPARTURE.
            Mr. Nestor Gianadis, the well-known head
            of the cigarette industry of Egypt,[and Presi-
            dent of the Union des Fahricanto de Cigarettes
            d’Egypte, is leaving Alexandria on Saturday
            by the Austrian Lloyd steamer for Trieste, on
            his way to America, with the intention of
            starting a factory at Boston, the first of its
            kind established in that oonntry, or, in fact,
            in any other, and where Egyptian cigarettes
            will be manufactured out of Egypt. This new
            departure was decided upon in consequence ot
            the vexations regulations of the United States
            customs, and the nnmerona restrictions im-
            posed upon the importation of cigarettes from
            this country ; so that whilst the exports from
            Cairo and Alexandria to European and Far
            Eastern countries has been increasing by leaps
            and bounds within the past five years or so,
            that to the U. S. of America has remained
            practically stationary.
            Mr. Gianaclis will also visit Germany and
            England before embarking for New York and
            will be absent until December.
            AMATEUR ESTATE BROKERS.
            We qnite agree with what a writer stated
            in the columns of a Cairo contemporary yester-
            day, that the Government should at oree
            pat a stop to the scandal of petty employ^
            in several state Departments, notably the
            Ministries of Finanoe and Interior, acting as
            land brokers. Naturally the genuine brokers
            and firms engaged in this class of business
            are np in arms and intend making complaint
            to the chiefs of the departments in which
            some of their employes are aoting as brokers,
            and who, undoubtedly, can bavefho know-
            ledge of what is going in this direction.
            We think that an enquiry should be opened
            without delay by the responsible heads, and
            measures be taken to stop what amounts to
            a grave scandal.
            SAN STEFANO CA8INO.
            The following is the programme of the vocal
            part of the ooncert to he given to-morrow
            , ». Mora-Amor U tM» - ■	.___...
            1 b. Mottlnato—Loonrarallo— P™	oioranoui
            t Noflotofolo—Morta 41 Northern* - HUo Ourtool
            I Dob F*>MtUso — BooUatWe • Bamanra — borjtoo — Ur.
            Onmlo
            4 Tom Srt 4««»lin>-r»co pto-mi<OMrtoa1.
            We have reoeived the following aooount from
            our Tahta (correspondent of the murder of the
            omdeh of Fazareh, whioh we reoorded In oar
            issne of yesterdaySheikh Genawi, the omdeh
            of Faztreh in the Tahta district, was the victim
            last Wednesday night of a brutal plot whioh
            was planned against him. The authors of the
            horrible oeimesat fire to a large rick of dried
            maize belonging to one of them, and then called
            the omdeh ont to take charge of the work of
            extinguishing the fire. Genawi rushed ont as
            soon as appealed to but no sooner did he reach
            the scene of the fire than he wm struck by two
            bullets. His wounds proved fatal in a very short
            time. Before expiring the omdeh named
            seven men whom he suspected of being parti-
            cipators in the dastardly act.
            As soon as Mohamed Helmi Effendi Issa,
            Si bstitnte of the Parquet, learnt. wfcat ha<
            happened, he went to the scene of the murder
            and held an inquiry. From this it was made
            dear that the seven men mentioned by Sheikh
            Genawi had been present at the fire and, as
            they were known to have cherished a great
            dislike to the omdeh, they were arrested. A
            woman, who was watching the fire, was also
            shot in the head, bnt it is believed that this
            was accidental, all the shots being intendec
            for the omdeh.
            uuieu.
            THE COTTON WORM.
            SPORT AND PLAY.
            KHEDIVIAL YACHT Cl UB.
            DEEP SEA RACE TO ABOUK1R AND
            - '	BACK.
            Conditions of thb Race.
            His Highness Prince Aziz, Commodore of
            the Khedivial Yacht Clnb haa offered a hand-
            some cup to be raced for under the following
            conditions :—
            1.	The race shall take plaoe on Sunday,
            September 3.
            2.	The start shall be from R to W. over •
            line drawn between the starter’s kiosk at the
            club house and the mole lighthouse round the
            ireakwater lighthouse, starboard hand; Boghea
            leaoon, starboard hand; to Abonlrir, rounding
            Kelson's Island on the starboard hand, and
            back rounding again the Boghas beacon, Port
            land ; and breakwater -lighthouse, Port
            land; and finishing across the line from
            W. to B. Distance about 40 miles. (No boats
            are to go through the “Hole in the Wall.’’)
            8.— The boats will start all together at
            10.80 s.m. and they will be expeoteff haok
            between 5 and 6 p.m., when his Highness will
            be •lAt'SJome” to members of the Club at the
            dub house>The handioap allowance will be
            made at the end of the race.
            4.	— At 10.20 a.m. a preparatoiy gun will
            be fired for those sailing to check time by, also
            another at 10.25 a.m. and one minnte before
            the start, viz. at 10.29 a.m., another gnn will
            be fired snd the Club burgee broken at the
            starter’s mast, when all boats mnst be under-
            way ; at 10.30 a.m., the time of start, a final
            gnn will be fired and the bargee healed down
            as a signal for all boats to start Any boat
            aoross the line before this final gnn is fired will
            have to return and recroea in aocordanoe with
            the racing roles.
            5.	— At least five boats mnst be entered for
            the raoe or there will be no start
            6.	— The handicap will be made mwwdlng
            to merits by a special committee composed of
            members not taking part in the race, and will
            be based on the doings of the boats in the
            ordinary weekly regattas. A gun will be fired
            as each boat crosses the line finishing.
            7.	— Entries must be lodged with the hon-
            orary secretary not later than to-day, after the
            regatta. There will be no entrance fee.
            8.	— Every boat intending to take pert
            must be at the Yaoht Clnb jetty not later than
            9.30 a.m. on the day of the raoe and will not
            be allowed to start until the boat and all its
            gear, inolnding rigging, eto. has been certified
            seaworthy by a speoial oommittee appointed
            for that purpose and. also mast be provided
            withsoffioient life buoys or preservers for the
            whole of its orew in oese of aooident.
            A speoial boat will be told off to afuise in
            the vioinity of Nelson’s Island to give assist-
            ance in the event of an aooident, also an
            umpire’s launch will follow the boats aB the
            way to observe the raoing end aot as a stand-by
            for breakdowns.
            The most Dotioeable item of the cotton-
            worm reports for last week is the considerable
            rednotion in the area attacked by the worm
            in the Behera district, the difference between
            that period and the preceding week being
            2,062 feddans. Damietta shows no recurrence,
            and can, therefore, be said to be entirely free,
            as in the preceding week only 9 } feddans
            were attacked. A diminution of 289 § feddans
            is reported from Gharbieh, and 105 from
            Dakahlieb, bnt in Minieh an area 16 kirats
            (§ feddan) have suffered. This province has
            been entirely free oi the worm, for several
            weeks, and its appearance now has been among
            the heghazi bersim, and qot in the cotton
            crop.
            The following are the foil details
            Gharbieh 86 i feddans, belonging to 6
            proprietors, have been cleared by lift children.
            Behera : - 804 feddans, ont of 884 attaeked
            belonging to 88 proprietors, have been cleared
            by 1,116 ohildren.
            Dakablieh :—4' feddans, belonging to 1 pro-
            prietor, have been otearod by 80 okildren,
            Minieh :-16 kirats of heghazi bersim beve
            been attaeked and oleerod of the worm,
            Calendar of Coming Events
            ALEXANDRIA.
            August
            Wed. 30 Partial Solar Eclipse. 2.59 to 5.19
            p.m.	'
            K. Y. C. Regatta. 3.30 p.m.
            Max. Prince’s Restaurant, das Bains.
            Roumanian orohestxa,every after
            noon. Sundays, morning.
            Windsor Hotel. Orchestra. 6 to
            11.30p.m. everyday.
            ? Alban,bra. Italian company in
            Bean. 9.15 p.m.
            Crown Casino,Ibrahimicb.9.30p.nii
            Theatre of Varieties (ex Ciccolani);
            9.80 p.m.
            Thurs. 31 San Stefano Casino. Bracale Benefit
            Concert 9 30 p.m.
            September.
            Sat. 2 A. C. C. ground, A. C, C. v. next
            XVI. 1.80 p.m.
            Alexandria Swimming Clnb. Meet
            Cuftr ms Gate 23. 4.30 p.m,
            CAIRO.
            August.
            Wed. 30 PartialSolarEolipse. 3.8to5.20pm.
            Esbekieh Theatre. Italian Comedy
            Company. 9.15 p.m.
            Theatre des Ambassadenra. 9.80
            p.m.
            Theatre des Nouveautos. 9.80 p.m.
            Alcazar Parisian. English Troupe.
            9.30 p.m.
            September.
            Fri. 1 Esbekieh Gardens. Performance.
            by British Military Bind. • to
            11 p.m.
            Turn. 5 Esbekieh Gardens. Performance by
            British Military Bend. 9 to II
            p.m.
            CARLTON HOTEL.
            ■Men (me muhim >
            RAMLKH’B FASHIONABLE HOTEL.
            riJMMW *V ™ uun‘_. _
            M r„r -	NWeewkm
            * e aouiuna fm*m

            <!-- ***** END OF DIV TAG FOR PAGE *****--></div>
            <div type="page" n="4"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="5"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="6"> </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>



﻿
